mediassistindia.net 2013-10-12

# Medi Assist.com - Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to us. Maintaining your trust and confidence is one of our highest priorities. We ensure secure transactions and follow customer privacy policy of high standards.

We state hereunder our information gathering and dissemination practices.

By using our website you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of our privacy policy. If you do not agree please do not access or use our website. This policy is subject to change at anytime without prior notice. We therefore request you to go through our privacy policy frequently to be updated with changes incorporated from time to time. 

As used in this Privacy Policy, terms such as "we" or "our" or “us” and "Company" refer to Medi Assist India TPA Private Limited and its current and future affiliate entities.

1\. Collection of Information and Usage:

We collect certain personal and non-personal information about you classified as mandatory and non-mandatory when you use our website. 

Personal Information shall include but not limited to your name, date of birth, gender, contact information like your telephone and mobile numbers, residential address, e-mail id etc. While using some of our services you would be required to give us your personal information for creating a User ID or registering on our website or providing financial information while placing an order with us, communicate with our Customer Care by call, email or otherwise. You may also choose to go through our website without providing us your information in which case you will not be able to have access to few of the sections in the website and thereby miss out on few of our services. 

Also you would be required to give us certain personal sensitive information about you such as your medical records including but not limited to your prescription, test reports, past medical history etc., We understand that these information are extremely private to you and assure you that these information will be used only for providing required healthcare services as mutually agreed to be rendered by us. . Also you are given the privilege to upload your medical records with us and store the same to which only you shall have access to using User ID unique to you. This will help you have access to all your medical records from anywhere in the world at a click away. We would again like reiterate here that barring you no one shall have access to these records and the same shall be transmitted to us in encrypted form to avoid being hacked and decoded enroute transmission. 

Also if you transact with us, we collect some additional information, such as your billing address, a credit / debit card number and a credit / debit card expiration date and/ or other payment instrument details.

We would like to state that we collect information that is absolutely necessary and relevant for us to make your experience hassle-free, convenient, smooth and most importantly safe. This also will help us in providing you with customized services, assist you with all your queries and set right the issues faced by you, to follow up with you in order to ensure a long, sustained relationship, most importantly to safeguard you from any kind of fraudulent and unlawful usage.

We use data collection devices such as "cookies" on certain pages of the Website to help analyse our web page flow and promote trust and safety. "Cookies" are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing our services. We offer certain features that are only available through the use of a "cookie".

We also use cookies to allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session. Most cookies are "session cookies," meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session. You are free to decline our cookies if your browser permits you to do so although we recommend strongly that you allow them to ensure you have access to all of our services.

2\. Sharing of Information:

We respect your privacy and hereby declare we do not disclose your information except as under:

**.** To law enforcement agencies in connection with an investigation having the interest of general public at large, after having been approved by the due process of law

**.** To our associates and affiliates to help detect and prevent fraud, identity theft and other illegal activities, correlate related or multiple accounts to prevent abuse of our services; and to facilitate joint or co-branded services that you request where such services are provided by more than one corporate entity

**.** We shall also share such information with our associates or affiliates should the company decide to undergo restructuring in anyway or is acquired by any other identity and ensure that in such an event the other identity continues to follow this policy strictly.

**.** You would be required to submit your financial information while making an online purchase from us or while booking for health checks. We use an online payment gateway that is operated by a third party and the extremely sensitive information which you provide like your credit-card details are transacted upon secure sites of approved payment gateways which are digitally under encryption, thereby providing the highest possible degree of care as per current technology.

3\. Advertisements and links to third- party websites:

Our website may contain certain advertisements and links to third-party websites. We would like to clarify that we do not control or guarantee the accuracy, safety and integrity of the information you provide, if you choose to, to these advertisers and third party websites. It is therefore advised that you go through their privacy policy before providing any information about yourself on these websites.

4\. Safety Precautions:

We have stringent, strong security measures undertaken to ensure against the loss, misuse or alteration of your information with us. We shall take all necessary precautions to safeguard your information and protect it from any unauthorized use. We have SSL Certificate issued by VeriSign and other safety measures in place to guard your information with us against any theft or unlawful usage or modification thereof. You are advised, however, that internet technology is not 100% safe and you should exercise discretion on using the same. 

Notwithstanding anything contained in this Policy or elsewhere, we shall not be held responsible for any loss, damage or misuse of Your Personal Information, if such loss,damage or misuse is attributable to a Force Majeure Event (as defined below).

A  **"Force Majeure Event"** shall mean any event that is beyond the reasonable control of Medi Assist and shall include, without limitation, sabotage, fire, flood, explosion, acts of God, civil commotion, strikes or industrial action of any kind, riots, insurrection, war, acts of government, , unauthorised access to computer data and storage device, computer crashes, breach of security and encryption, etc. 

5\. Consent:

By using our website and providing your information you consent to the collection and usage of your information by us as per the terms of this Privacy Policy. Kindly frequent this section to keep yourself updated of any changes made by us in the privacy policy.

6\. Grievance Officer:

The name and contact details of the Grievance Officer is provided hereunder to address all your queries and grievances in accordance with the Information Technology Act 2000 and rules made there under. 

Grievance officer: 

Email ID:[grievance.officer@mediassistindia.com ](mailto:grievance.officer@mediassistindia.com)

Contact No: 91-80-26584811

Medi Assist India TPA Private Limited,  
# 47/1, 9th Cross,  
1st Main Road, Sarakki Industrial Layout,  
3rd Phase, J P Nagar,  
Bangalore- 560078 

7\. Governing rules and law:

If you choose to visit the Website, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Policy and the Website's Terms of Use. In addition to the foregoing, any disputes arising under this Policy shall be governed by the laws of India.
